pcpitstop.com 2002-06-05

# Privacy Statement

PC Pitstop Privacy Policy 

  | 

Your privacy is important to us. By participating in the Council of Better Business Bureau's BBBOnLine� Privacy Program, we have made a commitment to meet the program's strict requirements regarding how we treat your information and have it verified by BBBOnLine. Further information about this program is available at http://www.  
bbbonline.org. 

* * *

_Other content certifications:_

---|---  
  
**Last Amended:** April 23, 2002

Effective March 1, 2000 

Table of Contents

  * Our Commitment to Privacy: We Look at PCs, not People

  * The Information We Collect

  * How We Use Information

  * Cookies

  * Technology Licensing

  * Banner Advertising

  * Support Board (BBS)

  * Our Commitment to Data Security

  * How You Can Access or Correct Your Information

  * How to Contact Us

Our Commitment to Privacy: We Look at PCs, not People

We at PC Pitstop want you to _love_ our site. So much so that you tell your friends about our services, and come back time and time again. In order to achieve this, in addition to having a fantastic, leading-edge site, we also need you to trust us--a lot, like you trust your doctor and your car mechanic. And that’s where privacy comes in. We’re going to go overboard to ensure your privacy.

The entire privacy issue centers around one simple concept: customer choice. We believe that our customers choose to return to our site, and they believe that we are committed to making an even better site. That’s our commitment to you. You won’t receive any solicitations from us, ever. And we will not send you e-mail without your permission. Moreover, we will never release your e-mail address for a fee or, for that matter, any other reason. Our business is providing a fantastic diagnostic Web site, not intruding on our customers' privacy.

Plus, throughout the entire diagnostic process of our tests, we’ll tell you exactly what’s going on and why. In this way, you can choose whether you want to continue or not. You see, it’s all up to you. Customer choice.

To better protect your privacy we provide this notice explaining our complete online information practices and the choices you can make about the way your information is collected and used. To make this notice easy to find, we make it available on our home page and at every point where personally identifiable information may be requested. 

The Information We Collect

The tests at PC Pitstop prompt you to _voluntarily_ enter your name and e-mail as part of our login process. While we strongly suggest you provide this information for greater accuracy and convenience in testing (see How We Use Information below), these two pieces of information are not required. You may use the site anonymously. Names and e-mail addresses are kept strictly confidential and are never distributed outside of PC Pitstop (see How We Use Information for more). 

In addition, the tests at PC Pitstop require that several small utilities--or **DLLs** \--are installed on your system to help collect PC information vital to our service and testing. These DLLs are detailed in our FAQ: http://www.pcpitstop.com/faq.asp#pcpitstop. 

Along with **signed ActiveX controls and JavaScript** , these utilities exercise and collect information from Windows about various components of your PC. This includes information on: 

  * Your system board and BIOS, CPU(s), memory configuration, disk drives, disk controllers, video board, monitor, Internet configuration, Windows configuration (such as version, free resources, fonts installed and more), running programs and security configuration. 

  * The tests, DLLs and controls at PC Pitstop never access any personal information--such as documents, files, downloads--stored on a PC, nor do they collect any information beyond their reason for downloading. 

We also use **cookies** on the site (and only our site). Only one of the cookies is required to run our programs; the rest are optional. For a full explanation of the cookies we use--and how we use them--see the Cookies entry of this statement. 

How We Use Information

The information we collect about your PC is stored in our database, analyzed, then presented back to you in summary and detailed reports, along with any tips that you can implement to improve system performance. How you use these recommendations is up to you; the tips are not automatically implemented. 

In some cases, AutoFixes are made available to correct specific settings on your system. AutoFixes are compact utilities written by PC Pitstop that you use voluntarily; they are never downloaded or executed without your permission, and an explanation detailing what changes will be made accompanies each fix. While the changes an AutoFix makes may not always be reversible, the utilities themselves are easily removable: Simply delete the AutoFix file from the directory to which you downloaded it. For more on PC Pitstop AutoFixes, see http://www.pcpitstop.com/pcpitstop/AutoFix.asp. 

The personal information that you voluntarily give us (name and e-mail address) is kept strictly confidential. Your address will not be sold or made available outside of PC Pitstop. We only use your e-mail address to assist in our correspondence with you if you have a question or concern about your test results. 

PC Pitstop's TechExpress feature gives users the opportunity to e-mail their tests results to friends, colleagues or support technicians. The feature will send a unique link to a user's results (with no password-protection) to an e-mail address(es) he/she specifies. The link will work for only one week from the time it was mailed. However, once the link and results are made public, PC Pitstop--despite its rigorous privacy measures--cannot guarantee the security of the user's results. PC Pitstop advises its visitors to act responsibly and use common sense about to whom they send their results. 

Also, PC Pitstop periodically distributes an e-mail newsletter to your e-mail address. You choose whether you want to receive mail from us when you create your login. If you submit your e-mail address to us for testing purposes, but later decide not to receive the newsletter, you can remove yourself from the mailing list at any time: 

  * Visit our site at http://www.pcpitstop.com/pcpitstop

  * Log in using the form in the left-hand column. 

  * Then click the "Change Login" link. 

  * Uncheck the box labeled "Send me updates on PC Pitstop's new features" and click Submit. 

Lastly, as part of our **market research model** , we collect aggregate information about all of the PCs tested at our site. This information includes average CPU speed, hard drive size, average free capacity, types of removable storage devices installed, most commonly installed software and so on. This is derived directly from the PC Pitstop tests described above. During this process, your anonymity will be 100% protected. We only look at trends in totality, not at the individual level. Ever. Hence, our motto: “We look at PCs, not people.” Examples of the types of market research reports we produce can be found here: http://www.pcpitstop.com/research. All of our research reports are publicly viewable. 

Cookies

To be able to remember your computer's test results as you browse from page to page, we use cookies. _We do not use cookies to track PCs in locations outside our site._ There are two types of cookies that we use at the PC Pitstop site: _session_ and _persistent_ cookies. Session cookies are only used for the duration of your visit, and help us keep your PC’s results associated with your browser session as you move through the site. Persistent cookies store data between visits to PC Pitstop, primarily for your convenience. You must accept some of these cookies for the site to work, but others are optional. 

No personal information is collected through the use of PC Pitstop's cookies. Details on all the cookies used at PC Pitstop are available here: http://www.pcpitstop.com/pcpitstop/aboutcookies.asp

**Third-party cookies:** Like most sites, PC Pitstop also uses banner advertising throughout its site. While some of these ads are served directly by PC Pitstop and do not employ cookies, most of the advertising is sold by third-party ad agencies and served by DoubleClick, an ad service which does place and collect cookie information. These cookies are used primarily to ensure that you do not view the same ad too many times, and also to track PC Pitstop as a referring site. However, we do not control the issuing or use of these cookies, and they are not required for proper operation of the PC Pitstop site. You may safely reject them, if you choose (see instructions here). The privacy policies for these ad companies differ from PC Pitstop's; you may review their policies and/or contact the agencies via their Web sites: 

  * DoubleClick: Serves ads for independent merchants 

  * PC World

  * Tribal Fusion

  * Commission Junction

For more information on cookies, including how to reject them, see http://www.pcpitstop.com/pcpitstop/aboutcookies.asp. 

Technology Licensing

PC Pitstop licenses its technology and database engine to third parties, but at no time is personally identifiable information ever sold, exchanged or disclosed in any form. In addition, we require that licensing parties adhere to the strict privacy policies regarding personally identifiable information outlined in this statement. 

Banner Advertising

PC Pitstop has partnered with PCWorld.com to sell advertising on PCPitstop.com. While PC Pitstop has no cookies associated with ads served directly from PC Pitstop, PCWorld.com has contracted with DoubleClick to serve advertising on www.pcpitstop.com. When DoubleClick is serving ads, it recognizes certain types of non-personally identifiable information, such as a user's IP address, browser version or type, operating system, service provider and time zone. DoubleClick also uses cookies to note the general content of the sites you visit over time in order to serve ads on this site and other sites. Furthermore, PCWorld.com uses so-called "web beacons" (also referred to as "clear gifs" or "pixel tags") provided by DoubleClick to help manage online advertising. These web beacons allow DoubleClick to recognize a browser's cookie when a browser visits this site. Although DoubleClick does share with PCWorld.com the non-personally identifiable information described above, such information is strictly in the aggregate. 

PC Pitstop Support Board (BBS)

The PC Pitstop bulletin board service (BBS) is located at [http://support.pcpitstop.com/cgi-bin/Ultimatebb.cgi](http://support.pcpitstop.com/cgi-bin/ultimatebb.cgi) and is powered by Infopop (http://www.infopop.com). It is used only as a means of disseminating technical support about issues within PC Pitstop. Any postings you make on the BBS will become publicly viewable. 

The Support BBS requires user registration to post an entry. This registration is independent of the main PC Pitstop registration system, and gives you the opportunity to customize your profile. The registration system requires a username (profile name), password and e-mail address; the user's city, state, country, occupation, home page, interests, ICQ number and an electronic signature are optional. However, with the exception of the user's e-mail address (which the user has the option to hide) and password (which is not publicly viewable), all information entered in the registration will be publicly viewable. Note: Passwords for the BBS are not encrypted and can be seen by the BBS administrators. In addition, users have the option of allowing a PC Pitstop BBS administrator to contact them via e-mail to help clarify support issues. 

Users may change their profile at any time by clicking on the Profile link at the top of the BBS page and then entering their username and password. 

We review all messages, and reserve the right to remove any messages that do not pertain to PC Pitstop or related topics and subject matter.

Our Commitment to Data Security

To prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy and ensure the correct use of information, we have put in place appropriate physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online. 

How You Can Access Or Correct Your Information

If you have created an account, you can access to review all your personally identifiable information that we collect at any time by browsing to http://www.pcpitstop.com/pcpitstop/default.asp and logging in with your e-mail address and password. You may then change your login information by selecting the Change Login link. We use this procedure to better safeguard your information. If you have forgotten your password, we provide a mechanism that e-mails your password to you. 

To protect your privacy and security, we will also take reasonable steps to verify your identity before granting access or making corrections. 

For instructions on changing your BBS profile, see the PC Pitstop Support Board (BBS) section above. 

How to Contact Us

Should you have any other questions or concerns about these privacy policies, please send us e-mail at [webmaster@pcpitstop.com](mailto:webmaster@pcpitstop.com).
